So, what's going on in this code?
这个代码是怎么回事
We have this list variable called lengths,
我们有这个列表变量
and all of these numbers inside of it.
以及里面的所有数字
Then we have this turtle setup code that's pretty familiar by now.
然后我们就有了这个海龟设置代码 现在已经很熟悉了
Then we have for length in lengths. What's that?
那么我们就有长度的长度了 那是什么
The key to understanding this line is knowing that length is
理解这条线的关键是知道长度是
a variable in a for loop can assign things to that variable.
For 循环中的变量可以将事物分配给该变量
It doesn't use an equal sign,
它不使用等号
but it's doing something similar to assignment statements that you've seen before,
但它和你以前见过的赋值语句一样
such amy=turtle.Turtle() or pretty_color = "blue".
yamy=turtle.Turtle () 或 pretty_color = "blue"
Remember that the loop will run once for each of the items in the list.
请记住 该循环将对列表中的每个项运行一次
In this case, there are 10 items in the list.
在这种情况下 列表中有 10 项
So the loop will run 10 times,
这个循环会运行 10 次
and each time the loop runs,
每次循环运行
it will take one of the items in the list,
它会把清单中的一个项目
and assign that item to the length variable.
并将该项分配给长度变量
The first time through the loop,
第一次通过这个循环
length gets assigned the first item in the list,
长度会分配到列表中的第一个项
which is the integer 10.
是 10 的整数
The second time through the loop,
第二次通过这个循环
length gets assigned 20.
长度指定为 20
The third time through,
第三次
it gets assigned 30, and so on.
它被分配了 30 等等
Again, you don't see any assignment statements here,
再说一遍你在这里没看到任何赋值语句
but this is working very much as if we had a line like length = 10,
但这很像我们的线长 10
and then length = 20,
然后长度 = 20
and then length = 30, and so on.
然后长度 = 30  等等
We don't need to actually have these assignment statements
我们不需要有这些赋值语句
because the assignment happens as part of the for loop.
因为赋值是作为 for 循环的一部分发生的
That's how for loops work,
这就是循环工作的方法
but how does this affect the shape of the turtle is drawing?
但这对乌龟的形状有何影响 ?
Well, you may have noticed that the length variable is also being used in this line.
那么您可能已经注意到 这个长度变量也在这个行中使用
Each time through the loop,
每次通过这个循环
this line does something slightly different.
这条线有点不同
The first time through,
第一次通过
length has been assigned a value of 10,
长度已赋值为 10
so the line works exactly the same as if you had typed this line instead.
所以这条线和你输入的线完全一样
But the second time through the loop,
但第二次通过这个循环
length gets assigned a value of 20,
长度的值为 20
so the line now works as if it were dizzy.forward(20).
所以现在这条线就像 dizzy.forward (20)一样
This continues for each number in the list.
这将针对列表中的每个数字继续
The result is that each time through the loop,
结果是每次循环
dizzy moves forward by a different amount.
头晕以不同量向前移动
Here's a way to talk about this sort of loop.
这是一种谈论这种循环的方法
We say that it's looping over the list which is to say,
我们说它在名单上
it's doing something for each item in the list.
它正在为列表中的每个项做一些事情
Something to be careful of though,
要小心一点
the first line of a for loop always ends with a colon.
循环的第一行总是以冒号结尾
The lines inside the loop are always indented by the same number of spaces.
循环中的行总是被相同数量的空格缩进
If you leave off the colon,
如果你离开结肠
or have mismatched indentation,
或者有不匹配的缩进
Python will give you a syntax error on the affected line,
Python 将在受影响的行上给出语法错误
so be sure to watch your syntax
所以一定要注意你的语法